The Earth will shake and tremble.
The Testament of Ann Lee is a drama, history,
music film directed by Mona Fastvold.
The extraordinary true legend of Ann Lee, founder of the
devotional sect known as the Shakers.
Ann Lee, played by Amanda Seyfried.
William Lee, played by Lewis Pullman.
Mary Partington / Narrator, played by Thomasin McKenzie.
James Whittaker, played by Matthew Beard.
Abraham Standerin, played by Christopher Abbott.
Nancy Lee, played by Viola Prettejohn.
The Testament of Ann Lee is a 2025 epic historical musical drama film
directed by Mona Fastvold, who co-wrote it with Brady Corbet.
The film stars Amanda Seyfried as Ann Lee, the founding leader of
the Shakers religious sect in the 18th century.
The supporting cast includes Thomasin McKenzie, Lewis Pullman, Stacy
Martin, Tim Blake Nelson, and Christopher Abbott.
The Testament of Ann Lee had its premiere in the main competition of the 82nd Venice International Film Festival on 1 September 2025, where it was nominated for the Golden
Lion, and was given a limited theatrical release in the United States on 25 December and the United Kingdom on 20 February 2026 by Searchlight Pictures.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with Seyfried receiving acclaim for her performance (often described as
"career-best") and earning nominations for the Golden Globe Award and the Critics' Choice Award for Best Actress.
The film explores themes of new york city, christianity,
celibacy, musical, evangelical christianity.
The tone is emotional.